Ahmed Mansour

Civil Engineer with 5 Years Experience and have a deep passion for Computer Science. Experienced in site engineering and project coordination. Skilled in programming and software development, with completed projects in Python, Flask, and SQL.

Skills

Programming Languages:

- Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL.
- Flask, API Integration, Database Management.

Design & Drafting Software

• AutoCAD, Civil 3D, Revit And other Surveying Programs.

Work Experience

Site Engineer

Farag Sultan Contracting and Transportation Establishment

Jun 2021 - Jun 2023

- Managed the installation of interlock pavement and asphalt roads, ensuring quality standards.
- Coordinated and executed substitution layers for multiple roads and roundabouts.
- Ensured compliance with project deadlines and quality control.

Consulting Engineer

Housing And Building National Research Center

Jul 2020 - May 2021

- · Supervised carpentry, metalwork, and concrete construction activities.
- Conducted quality control inspections for residential zones.
- Managed construction activities and ensured compliance with safety regulations.

Executive Engineer

El-Masrawyah Building & Construction

Mar 2019 - May 2020

- Led engineering-related project activities and coordinated with stakeholders.
- Supervised daily construction activities to meet engineering specifications.

Executive Engineer

Al-Maraj Building & Construction

Apr 2018 - Feb 2019

- Maintain accurate records of progress, daily reports, and any issues encountered on-site and prepare periodic progress reports for senior management and stakeholders.
- Directed design and construction of various foundation types, including slab-on-grade, deep foundations, and pile foundations for residential, commercial, and industrial buildings.

Contact

Cairo, Egypt +20 - 100 9069 364 nabilahmed0100@gmail.com Github | Portfolio | Linkedin

CS Projects

MAL API Project

A Web application made by flask and it uses MyAnimeList API to Fetch Anime Details.

Github Link

Youtube Downloader With GUI

GUI Program Made with Python, that uses yt_dlp, tkinter and ttkbootstrap libraries.

Github Link

MAL Anime Details Scraper

A Python program that uses the MyAnimeList API to Fetch Data From A Text file That contain 1 Anime in a line and save it into a Database file. Additionally, creates a (.csv) file containing all the data saved in the Database file based on the filter given.

Github Link

Certifications & Courses

CS50's Introduction to Programming with Python Certified (CS50P)

CS50's Introduction to Computer Science Certified (CS50X)

Education

Degree:

Bachelor of Civil Engineering

University Name:

Higher Institute of Engineering and Technology in Kafr El Sheikh